[music]
>> Welcome back to Scoreline. The Ballon
d'Or going to be awarded at the end of
next month. So, let's see who is up for
it. This is the crème de la crème in
world football starting with Jude
Bellingham, Kylian Mbappé, of course in
there as well as Michael Olise, Harry
Kane heavy favorite, Khvicha
Kvaratskhelia for PSG. No question has a
shout to potentially win this award.
>> You could give it to a lot of those
names and I think everybody would be
very happy. Alex and then
>> back with you though. We're going to
tell you who should win it and at least
make the case for the favorites. And
there are a lot of names on there that
are deserving, but there are also some
that really stand out, right?
>> Yeah, I mean especially if you look at
the the bookies favorites as to who's
going to win this trophy, you would see
that there's clearly one player who has
an advantage right now. And why would
you bet against that player? And that
player being Harry Kane. With the goals
that he's scored, the performances put
out there, you have to say you're a bit
crazy if you go against these types of
odds. This tells me that the bookies
know something that we don't. I actually
broke it down to the percentage as well.
It is 63.6%
probably that he's going to actually
lift that trophy. And why would you bet
against it? Of course, listen, we're
here in an entertainment business. And
here's the guy who's scoring the most
goals above anybody else right now
across obviously multiple competitions.
For Bayern Munich, let's focus on that
alone. It is 61 goals in 51 Bayern
games. That's what we're looking at for
Ballon d'Or
>> stats and the status. I do think that
when you look at what he did for do for
England during the World Cup, it's also
truly exceptional. And he's someone
who's taken his form from what he did do
domestically into that World Cup and
almost led the three lines to a real
triumphant tournament. But, there's no
real competitor as far as I'm concerned.
I understand it. Trophies tell you a big
story here. Spain had a tremendous
amount of success. Very happy for Lamine
Yamal, very happy for Rodri. But, Harry
Kane is on a a world of his own. If you
look at what he did do in the 51 games,
it's 1.20 goals per games on average.
That is on another planet, Alex.
So, he must be your favorite as well.
>> He's my favorite. He is
>> [music]
>> Tell me why. I mean, well, you already
talked about alluded to the goals. I
mean, his 73 goals is That's insane.
Like,
that is production that you just don't
see very often. So, yes, winning the
domestic treble, I like that. What puts
him over the top for me is you love to
look at stats, right? Everybody wants to
see how many goals, how many assists,
how many goals created.
What he has done to reinvent himself
inside that that Bayern Munich system,
that
>> Why Why do you say reinvent himself
though? Because he was already very good
at Tottenham. So, why do you say
reinvent himself?
>> Because I love the way that sometimes he
would track back and help defensively.
He changed base Sure, but I think he's
making more of an impact now, especially
because Bayern is such a team that is uh
looking for, you know, bigger trophies.
I mean, Tottenham wasn't really a team
that was going to bring home a potential
>> Champions League?
>> Tottenham weren't good enough. They
weren't good enough to win a Champions
League. Bayern Munich is a team that
could win the Champions League. I mean,
you finished just short of the winner in
the semi-finals by a goal. Yes, you are
a team that can win the Champions
League. And the impact there is
different than the impact that you can
have at Tottenham.
>> Listen, I think his goals and his
statistics are what's going to get him
the Ballon d'Or. Nothing else. I think
he's the same player as he was at
Tottenham. He played in the Premier
League, and obviously it was very
difficult to score goals there. He
scored a phenomenal amount of goals for
Tottenham Football Club. It was
ridiculous what he did do for that
football club, except didn't win a
trophy. He went to Bayern Munich, in my
personal opinion, to get ready for a
World Cup, to be able to extend his
career longer, and to be able to
potentially win a Ballon d'Or and a
World Cup with England. What he did do
for England in the World Cup, it was
seven games, six goals. That's
exceptional after the season he had for
Bayern Munich. It's absolutely no joke
what he did do. And I think you're
starting to see the respect that he's
getting from Kylian Mbappé, Lamine
Yamal, Pedri, all these other players
who are being asked, Kvaratskhelia,
about who they think's going to win
Ballon d'Or. Everyone says Harry Kane.
Now, I respect the performance, but
we've always seen the same from him. He
drops off, he plays these passes, his
assists are
incredible as well, but it's the goal
scoring, it's the stats that go into it.
He just broke an England all-time goal
scoring record at World Cups. He is
doing something that other players
haven't done. He's taken a chance by
going to another league away from the
Premier League, and he's an Englishman.
To do that, why? I mean, listen, right
now, if you were to look at the players
in world football, you'd have to say the
majority of them don't play in the
Premier League.
>> Mhm.
>> The majority of them play elsewhere. And
why? It's to do exactly what Harry
Kane's just done. He knew he could score
more goals in the Bundesliga. Why the
Bundesliga? Because it's the league with
the highest goals per game ratio. Why
Bayern Munich? Because they're cleaning
the floor with absolutely every opponent
they play against. Bayern are delighted
he's there. He's the main man at that
football club, 100%. But he's got to win
the big trophy there. You can't just go
there and win a Ballon d'Or and be happy
with that. Harry Kane, I think,
personally, is more interested in
winning a Champions League trophy with
Bayern Munich and cleaning up
domestically than he has winning a
Ballon d'Or. The decision to go to
Germany and play in the Bundesliga is
what's going to get him hands-on trophy
with that Ballon d'Or. And also what he
did do in a three lines jersey, which
hurts me to say, being someone who was
raised in Scotland.
>> Well, talk about trophies. Kylian Mbappé
coming up short, you know, for the last
couple of years. But, here is the thing
with Kylian Mbappé because when you look
at the numbers, you want to look at the
numbers, he outscored Harry Kane in the
World Cup, he outscored him in Champions
League as well. He won the Golden Boot
in both of them. Make a case for Kylian
Mbappé.
>> Well, he scored 11 less than obviously
Harry Kane did. So, that's where Harry
Kane gets the odds, and that's where the
odds lean in his favor. Kylian Mbappé is
a phenomenal player, obviously has an
enormous case because he was top goal
scorer in La Liga, as you pointed out
there, top goal scorer in the Champions
League. That is no joke. That
statistically gives him the opportunity
to to be successful. The 10 goals at the
World Cup was was unbelievable. It's 22
now he's scored in his career at the
World Cup. He is going to win many many
Ballon d'Ors and he should potentially
win this one. I mean, having the Golden
Boot obviously in La Liga is one thing
the Pichichi.
But no trophy to follow suit is maybe a
bit of a disappointment. I think he
would have more of a debate, more of an
argument had France gone all the way and
beaten Spain and got to that World Cup
final and won it. Then you have a better
case, a better argument because you're
not far away. Statistically it's
exceptional. But we've also critiqued
Kylian Mbappé for what he did do it for
Real Madrid this past season. The goals
are one thing.
The performances and sometimes missing
penalty kicks in big moments where he
missed opportunities, that's not
forgotten when it comes to awards like
this, individual awards. It's more about
consistency over these years and it's
crazy for me to say that with how many
goals he scored. He is one hell of a
player, right? 25 goals in La Liga, 15
obviously in the Champions League and 10
in the World Cup. When I say those
numbers, I feel silly by saying this guy
shouldn't win a Ballon d'Or. But
unfortunately for him, Harry Kane's in
the race.
>> How close do you think it is? Is this
one and two in your mind or does a guy
like Lamine Yamal factor into that as
well?
>> I think Rodri's win of the Ballon d'Or
tells us that we should expect the
unexpected when it comes to this
competition. I know Vinícius Júnior was
probably hard done by because of his
outgoing and statistical season that he
had at Real Madrid and what he did do
obviously win
the Champions League with Real Madrid
that season. Um but I do think that
winning the World Cup does have an
impact on it. I think we've seen that
clearly with Lionel Messi winning so
many. Of course he did do incredibly
well at Barcelona and then he's done
well at PSG, he's done well at Inter
Miami. But at the same time, I think
that this is going to be a one-horse
race. It's not a three-horse race. You
can throw Lamine Yamal's hat into it.
But he's more of a team player for Spain
during the World Cup than he was an
individual player. And I think this is
an individual award and it comes down to
statistics and consistency. And I think
Lamine Yamal, I'm going to throw this
out there, he will win Ballon d'Or many
times. But at the same time, his
statistics need to up a notch. He's been
that guy who's got himself into a
position where he's got close to 20
goals, 20 assists all season long. Last
season, it was incredible, right? He had
a 25 goals, 20 assists season. That's
phenomenal. But I still think it can be
better for Lamine Yamal. And if it is
better, he starts to creep into the
Lionel Messi category of player. Maybe
I'm crazy by saying that, but he's
surrounded by talented players at
Barcelona and Spain.
>> He's only 19 years old. I mean, and you
look at what he did leading the teenage
goal contributions in Champions League.
His day is coming. I am with you,
though. It's not this year. He's 19. And
think about how many more opportunities
he's going to have. He's a generational
player, and I think we are going to see
that. Any dark horse chara- characters
that you think might come out of the
way? But the one that jumps out to me is
Khvicha Kvaratskhelia, because if you
watch him, he has an impact on every
single match that he plays. But maybe
you could argue, okay, you know, the
numbers aren't exactly there. In
Champions League, they were, though. He
was exceptional. And most of that action
coming in the knockout stages when his
team needed him the most.
>> Well, you asked the question and took
the answer. I mean, Khvicha's the one
player. I mean, that's the truth. He is
the one player that probably stands out.
Rodri might be the other one who's
deserving of a shout because of what he
did do in the World Cup, but I don't
think he was as good at this World Cup
as he was in the Euros when they won it.
And also, what he did do for Manchester
City at that period of time. Um
Khvicha's unbelievable. His numbers
don't lie, but there's room for
improvement with him. PSG winning the
Champions League back-to-back is truly
exceptional. I will say this, Alex. The
reason why I think PSG have cleaned up
is because of his arrival. Remember, he
came through a winter transfer and
actually transformed that PSG season.
They They had to go through the playoffs
twice. And he's one of the reasons why
they got to a Champions League final.
These stats don't lie. Again, I go back
to what we're seeing with Lamine Yamal.
>> [music]
>> Not a striker, so it's very difficult to
have those types of numbers, Harry Kane,
and obviously the Lewandowskis who
didn't win a Ballon d'Or, but at the
same time the Messis and the Ronaldos,
they're not all out-and-out strikers,
right? So, I want to see better numbers
from these players. And I think Fekir,
playing a little bit more domestically,
will help him improve his statistics and
improve his chances of eventually going
on to win it. What hurts him now is his
national team, which I don't like. He
should be judged by his performance, how
much you entertain us. That's what
Ballon d'Or is to me. It's about the
entertainment factor and not necessarily
all the stats. But right now, as you
will see, Harry Kane's going to win this
because of the stats.
>> Harry Kane, I think we are both in
agreement. It's It's his. It's his. And
it's happening in London, which is
really cool. That's going to be awesome
to watch. But Harry Kane, you look at
the numbers
>> [music]
>> whatever way you slice them, this guy
was the absolute man this year for both
club and country. And so,